[Music]
the last cream comparison
Lucerne brand Safeways this is where I
got this from Sobe's any of that you
know group will likely sell this it's I
think it's western Canada only
but the important part of this whole
cream comparison is to highlight what
other crap they put in there
cream over here but this
18 fat
nothing else look
just there you can see it just milk and
cream
that's it this one has got
carrageenan I think
and wherever yes it does there and so
cream milk and Carrigan
carrigating that's not too bad just on
its own because you know I recommend
people put that as one of the
stabilizers for their ice cream
so I'm hoping that these two are good we
know
you know we've done Dairyland with the
same fat percentage so what I'm going to
do now is just knock up the two simple
batches of chocolate much like we did
with the Dairyland exactly the same as
we did for the luxury creams finally for
these two we'll churn them up and
compare all of the Ice Cream side by
side and decide which one is the best to
use in Canada for making your ice cream
[Music]
18 cream that's the one we're starting
with now from Lucerne we've got
everything in the pan we're going to get
it mixed up get it up to temperature
again exactly the same as the others
we're going to bring it up I haven't got
my digital thermometer or anything so
we're going to bring it out to the point
where it starts to steam hold it there
for two to three minutes something like
that and then we're going to take off
the heat and chill it down
foreign
[Music]
last one the last cream
that we're testing this is the Lucerne
33 whipping cream
just has carrageenan in it it's a really
nice
consistency comes out the the carton
really nicely it kind of
pause much better than I thought it
would
um again just to just to reiterate all
these six chocolate ice creams have been
very basic no stabilizers don't have any
at the moment
and they've all been based on 12 fat 10
milk solids non-fat 60 sugar and 40
total solids
all right this is a basic comparison to
see how the creams react and see how the
resulting ice cream
tastes we're gonna get this one warmed
up and pop it in the fridge to chew
along with the other one and then we'll
do one final
comparison of all six ice creams side by
side
before we determine the best Canadian
cream to make ice cream
[Music]
cream let's get that
blue made a mess
get that in the machine and churn it
[Music]
thank you
[Applause]
[Music]
pinching child stickers
this is the Lucerne 18 and we're gonna
go with something that looks like dogu
okay in the freezer
down there right
quick clean up swap over turn the other
one and get that one turned nice and
quick
last one
the
33 percent
very dark this one turn
[Music]
land so far right 33 percent
let's go for
a green fishing
kind of free as we go
[Music]
back in a couple of hours when we do the
final comparison of all the ice creams
together to see which is
the best
cream to use for your ice cream in
Canada and possibly the US
[Music]
there's some ice cream
six different chocolate ice creams all
done to the exact same specs I'll just
remind you again what those
are
that is
12 fat 10 milk solid on fat 16 sugar and
40 solids all with different creams so
there's lots of different numbers and
amounts of ingredients here
right so
we have
the Unicorn which was the 33 Dairyland
was the other Dairyland
the no sticker
and then we have
the cupcake
the vital Farms
Avalon
which is the cherries
the dogu which is the 18 Lucerne and the
the green fishy which is the 33
Lucerne so let's get the tubs off let's
put the lids off that's what I'm going
to say
lids
Lids lids
lids all com what am I looking over
there all get rid of that all completely
different shades of brown all
approximately the same amount I had to
use cups you know to measure cocoa
powder you can't get it the same
um but
we have this one which is the
virtual Farms
vital greens Farm 52 percent
ten dollars
let's
dive into this one
percentage was the result you know that
what you want for the best ice cream
this would win but
even at 12 it leaves this
greasy fatty film on your spoon tastes
nice it tastes really nice
smooth but it is fatty the next one is
this one which is the Avalon which
still got that fatty kind of texture to
it
bit icy need stabilizer but stabilizer
when you choose to put in
the Dairyland
creams
well it's got really weird
aftertaste
this must be there 33 it's got really
weird
After Cash
this is the 18
hatch much
better
yeah and then here we are the last two
the green fishy
which is the 33 Lucerne and the 18
Lucerne let's dig into this one
that's really good
that's really good that's the 18 percent
nope that's the dogu yeah I see 18
Lucerne that's really good
33 Lucerne
there's no winner
that's really good
so if you live in Canada
western Canada the winner is
this cream this is the cream you want to
use to make your ice cream with if you
live in western Canada if you don't and
you live somewhere else look at the fat
percentage but look at what's in it
because this
has carrageenan and that's it you know
you milk your creamy Carrigan this has
loads of stabilizers in this has
sodium citrate that's all that's much
better the 18 percent
much much better 33 Dairyland is rubbish
the expensive creams just not worth it
they just don't produce anywhere near as
good a result as this one which is this
the Lucerne 18 is also a really good
result so
of the three of the six creams here the
winner is the Lucerne 33 percent
the runner-up is the
is the Lucerne 18
and third place
Dairyland 18
cream so there we go in first second
third places all right
that's a lot of chocolate ice cream to
get through
anyway at least now we know which cream
we can use to make all our ice cream
from this point on so thanks so much for
watching don't forget to like And
subscribe and I'll see you next time
probably
good few kilos here
[Music]